<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Inca -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KHITAN_DESC</Tag>
		<English>The Kitanyes</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KHITAN_PEOPLES</Tag>
		<English>Khitan People</English>
	</TEXT>
                <TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EMPIRE_OF_KHITAN</Tag>
		<English>Empire of Liao</English>
	</TEXT>
                <TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KHITAN_JURCHEN</Tag>
		<English>Empire of Jin</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KHITAN_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Khitan Federation</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KHITAN_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Kitanyes</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KHITAN_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Khitan</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ABAOJI</Tag>
		<English>Yelu abaoji</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UP_KHI_TITLE</Tag>
		<English>The Power of Two Administrations:</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UP_KHI</Tag>
		<English>Reduced city distance maintenance and city maintenance.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_IRON_PAGODA</Tag>
		<English>Ironpagoda</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_IRON_PAGODA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB] "Iron Pagoda Horsemen" were an elite unit of the Jurchen Jin dynasty that was instrumental in the 30 year supremacy of the Jin State. Though they only served for no more than two decades, they were pivotal in no less than a dozen crucial battles and hundreds of skirmishes that secured the Jin realm. According to Prince Wuzhu's doctrine, the Iron Pagoda Cavalry would be a dedicated and concentrated vanguard that would maximize the already deadly thrust of the Jin cavalry charges, acting both as his best shock cavalry as well as specialized heavy dragoons that also frequently fought as dismounted heavy infantry.
		
		The Iron Pagodas were completely armored from head to toes in heavy lamellar armor - with only their eyes and hands exposed. Their horses were also completely encased in armor as well, covered on all sides with thick barding of lamellar plates and padded cotton. In fact, each armored rider would be given two horses to ensure mobility throughout the ranks and in all situations. They were also given a versatile array of weapons, aside from their customary lance, commonly featuring a black pennon, they were also equipped with a bow and full quiver, as well as a large two handed sword. For their dual roles (see below) they were also equipped with many sapping tools, including picks, rope ladders, and shovels. - Dragon's Armory</English>
		<French>[TAB] - Wikipedia</French>
		<German>[TAB] - Wikipedia</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Not translated.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Not translated.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UHV_KHI1_TITLE</Tag>
		<English>Establish trade with 3 Silk Road countries</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UHV_KHI1</Tag>
		<English>Establish trade with 3 Silk Road countries</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UHV_KHI2_TITLE</Tag>
		<English>Have 3 Wats, 1 Mosque, and 1 Fire Temple in 1150 AD</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UHV_KHI2</Tag>
		<English>Have 3 Wats, 1 Mosque, and 1 Fire Temple in 1150 AD</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UHV_KHI3_TITLE</Tag>
		<English>Control or Vassalize Korea, Song, and Jurchen</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UHV_KHI3</Tag>
		<English>Control or Vassalize Korea, Song, and Jurchen</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_KHITAN</Tag>
		<English>It's the year 901 AD. Abaoji has risen as head of the Yila tribe, the most powerful of all the Khitans to extablish the Liao Dynasty! The land of the steppes and northern forests is vast, but the aging dynasty of China has opened up new opprotunities as well. You must choose where to expand knowing that far flung vassals may one day rise against you.</English>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
